powertochange.com 2019-02-11

# The Life: Privacy Policy

### Who we are

The Life Project (operator of www.thelife.com) is a ministry of Power to Change Ministries (P2C), which in turn is part of Campus Crusade for Christ International (CCCI), a worldwide evangelistic and discipleship ministry with representative local ministries in over 160 countries. P2C is comprised of P2C as well as a number of local [ministries](https://p2c.com/) that operate within P2C. Throughout this document “we” and “ours” refers to the organization as a whole as well as to individual field ministries, and “you” and “yours” refers to any and all ministry partners and public site users.

### Our commitment to you

We are committed to protecting and appropriately handling private and personal information and take your privacy very seriously. This Privacy Policy describes how we collect, process, use, disclose, and share your personal information or personal data.

### How we protect your information

The security of your information is important to us. P2C has implemented safeguards to protect the information we collect. However, no website or Internet transmission is completely secure. We urge you to take steps to keep your personal information safe, such as choosing a strong password and keeping it private, as well as logging out of your user account, and closing your web browser when finished using P2C websites on a shared or unsecured device.

Some of our systems involve the storage and processing of your personally identifiable information outside of Canada using the services of third party service providers. Although we have undertaken measures, including obtaining contractual commitments, to safeguard your personally identifiable information whenever it is shared with other parties, if your personally identifiable information is stored or processed outside of Canada, it will also be subject to the laws of those other jurisdictions.

However, this does NOT apply to personal data – including sender and/or recipient e-mail addresses — contained in ordinary e-mail notes while these are en route between your computer and our servers, during which time these notes must be considered public data.

We will never send you e-mail notes containing any sensitive or private information such as credit card details, and strongly urge you to never place such information in emails.

## The information we collect from or about you

### Personal Information

For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, personal information is any information about an identifiable individual, other than an individual’s business contact information when collected, used or disclosed for the purposes of enabling the individual to be contacted in relation to their business responsibilities.

### Types of personal information we collect from you

_Account Information._ When you create an account on any of our sites, request information, purchase materials or donate to P2C or any of our ministries we collect your contact information such as: name, address, phone number, billing address (if different), payment information including credit card information (name, credit card number and credit card expiration date) and optionally an email address.

_Communications._ When you communicate with us (via email, phone, contact forms or otherwise), we may maintain a record of your communication.

_Automatically Collected Information About Your Activity._ We may use cookies, or other tracking technologies to automatically collect information about your activities only on any of our websites. We may also collect and store information that your computer or mobile device provides to us in connection with your use of our websites such as your browser type, type of computer or mobile device, browser language, IP address, mobile carrier, unique device identifier, location, and requested and referring URLs.

### How we use your information

If you visit any one of our websites we may place a cookie on your computer. (See section on cookies for an explanation). In addition, we may collect IP addresses for purposes of system administration, to calculate aggregate statistical information, to identify general usage records, and to measure traffic patterns for all visitors to our websites. These do not identify individual users but may be used for general statistical and auditing purposes.

We will not sell your personal information (such as your name and contact information) to third parties to use for their own marketing purposes. P2C may use the information we collect internally within our organization or within our ministries for the following purposes:

  * To provide better service to you.
  * To personalize your experience on any of our websites.
  * To personally contact you if necessary.
  * To ensure the effectiveness of our various electronic ministries.
  * To promote and encourage support of our ministry activities. We may use your personal information (including email address) to update you about our ministries, notify you about upcoming events and activities you may be interested or to solicit donations from you to further our ministry activities in by purchasing advertising space on third-party websites such as social media sites.
  * To provide you with electronic information or printed materials upon request. If you request electronic information or printed material via one of our web sites, or if you send us a comment or question via e-mail, we may keep your contact information (including name, address and email address) in a database. This will allow us to send you a reply, fulfill your order or to provide further information pursuant to your request.
  * Marketing and Promotions. For marketing and promotional purposes, we may send you information, newsletters, or promotions, or otherwise contact you about products or information we think may interest you, including information about third party products and services.
  * Analytics. To gather metrics to better understand how users interact with both our websites and third-party websites .
  * Comply with Law. To comply with legal obligations, as part of our general business operations, and for other business administration purposes.
  * Prevent Misuse. Where we believe necessary, we may investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person, or violations of our Terms of Service or this Privacy Policy.

In the event that you reside outside of the country of Canada, we may make this information available to one of our ministries or representatives in your locale so that they may initiate contact with you.

### How we share your information

We share information as set forth below, and where individuals have otherwise consented:

_Service Providers_. We may share your information with third party service providers who use this information to perform services for us, such as payment processors, hosting providers, auditors, advisors, consultants as well as those who assist us in providing information about our ministry activities.

_Affiliates_. The information collected about you may be accessed by or shared with ministries or representatives of P2C, whose use and disclosure of your personal information is subject to this Privacy Policy.

_Legally Required_. We may disclose your information if we are required to do so by law.

_Protection of Rights_. We may disclose information where we believe it necessary to respond to claims asserted against us or, comply with legal process (e.g., subpoenas or warrants), enforce or administer our agreements and terms, for fraud prevention, risk assessment, investigation, and protect the rights, property or safety of P2C, its users, or others. Cookies, pixels and tracking

We may use cookies, clear GIFs/pixel tags, JavaScript, local storage, log files, and other mechanisms to automatically collect and record information about your usage and browsing activities on our websites. We may combine this information with other information we collect about users. Below, we provide a brief summary of these activities.

  * Cookies. These are small files with a unique identifier that are transferred to your browser through our websites. They allow us to remember users who are logged in, to understand how users navigate through P2C websites, and to display personalized content and targeted information (including on third party sites and applications).
  * Pixels, web beacons, clear GIFs. These are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, which we use to track the online movements of users across our websites. We also use these in our emails to let us know when they have been opened or forwarded, so we can gauge the effectiveness of our communications.
  * Analytics Tools. We may use internal and third-party analytics tools, including Google Analytics.

### Advertising on third-party websites

We may use third parties, such social media websites, to allow us to provide you with information about our ministries, ministry activities, and online mentoring services. These third-party websites may use third-party cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies to collect information. They may also collect your device identifier, IP address, or identifier for advertising (IDFA). The information that these third parties collect may be used to assist us in providing you with more relevant information that we serve on our sites or elsewhere on the web, and as described above. Third-party cookies are covered by the third parties' privacy policy. For more information on third-party advertising-related cookies and how to opt-out of them, please visit one of the following third-party websites:

  * The Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising (available in English only)
  * Network Advertising Initiative Consumer Opt-Out (available in English only)

### Giving your consent to collect and use your information

You give us permission to collect and utilize as here described any of this personally identifiable information by making use of any of our online resources, including but not limited to:

  * Browsing any of our web sites;
  * Requesting information or materials via a web site;
  * Sending us an e-mail;
  * Completing a donation through any of our web sites;
  * Registering for a conference through any of our web sites;
  * Purchasing materials through any of our web sites.

### Changes to our privacy policy

If we change our privacy policies and procedures, we will post those changes on this page. If we make any changes to this Privacy Policy that materially change how we treat your personal information, we will endeavor to provide you with reasonable notice of such changes, such as via prominent notice on our websites or to your email address of record, and where required by law, we will obtain your consent or give you the opportunity to opt out of such changes. Accessing, updating or deleting your personal information

If you believe that the personal information that we hold about you is incorrect, or if you wish us to remove any information held about you, you may contact our Privacy Officer to ask us to update or delete that personal information. If you do not want us to use the personal information gathered about you through various means to contact you, you may request that we restrict or entirely eliminate sending you any mail or e-mail, other than what is required for legal reasons or operational necessity. To update or delete your information or request more details about this privacy policy, please contact the Privacy Officer by:

  * Telephone: (604) 514-2055
  * Mail: 20385 64 Avenue, Langley, BC V2Y 1N5 Canada
  * E-mail: privacy@p2c.com

For security reasons we will require verification of identity before taking any action, and you must be aware that certain information held for legal reasons or operational necessity may not be deleted.

### Protecting the privacy of children (under 13)

Although our web sites are primarily targeted at adult users, we may also choose to provide online resources for younger persons. Safeguarding the security and privacy of children is of paramount importance. Therefore, we will obtain verifiable parental consent prior to the collection of any personally identifiable information about children and will not knowingly give children the ability to post publicly or otherwise distribute personally identifiable contact information without prior verifiable parental consent.

### The limitations of our privacy policy

Any personal data voluntarily disclosed by you on bulletin boards, in chat rooms, in e-mail notes or in any other public forum provided by our organization, could potentially be accessed and “harvested” by third parties and is therefore not subject to our privacy policy. In addition, external web sites linked to by any of our web sites may not adhere to our Privacy Policy, and you should refer to their Privacy Policy to understand the rules under which they operate.
